Register to the Polskie Siły Zbrojne, Armia Polska na Wschodzie issuances, 1940-1946
Hoover Institution Archives
Polskie Siły Zbrojne, Armia Polska na Wschodzie issuances
1940-1946
46021
Hoover Institution Archives
40 manuscript boxes (16 linear feet)
Poland. Polskie Siły Zbrojne. Armia Polska na Wschodzie.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1946.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
The Armia Polska na Wschodzie (Polish Army in the East) was created on September 12th, 1942, by the direct order from the Commander-in-Chief of the Polish Armed Forces, General Władysław Sikorski. It was created through the merger of the Wojsko Polskie na Środkowym Wschodzie (Polish Army in the Middle East) and Armia Polska w ZSRR (Polish Army in the USSR). Per the order of Sikorski, General Władysław Anders was appointed as the commander of the force. Operationally, the forces were subject to the British, PAI (Persia and Iraq) force command. In June 1943, Armia Polska na Wschodzie became known as the Polish II Corps and was moved to Egypt and subsequently to the Italian front, where it helped the allies fight the Nazi Germany forces, including at the Battle of Monte Cassino.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection is composed of military manuals created by the British, German, and Soviet military and translated into Polish for the needs of the Polish Armed Forces in the East. Manuals are individually listed within 18 different series. Each series is representative of a topic within which corresponding manuals have been arranged. The topics covered are: artillery, anti-aircraft artillery, anti-armored artillery, chemical weapons, armored weapons, firearm, air force, communication, landing operations, soldier welfare, infantry, combat engineering, supply services, topography, and transport.
Poland. Polskie Sily Zbrojne Handbooks, manuals, etc.; World War, 1939-1945--Germany.; World War, 1939-1945--Great Britain.; World War, 1939-1945--Poland.; World War, 1939-1945--United States.
- Armia Brytyjska (British Army), 1940-1944
  Scope and Contents
  Comprised of British military manuals, outlining the army’s usage of abbreviations, campaigns from the northern African region, and military engineering procedures.
  - Angielskie Pozasłużbowe Zwyczaje Wojskowe, 1940 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Angielskie taktyczne skróty wojskowe, 1943 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Definicje, 1943 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Nauki z Kampanii I. Armii Brytyjskiej w Afryce Północnej, 1943 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Organizacja Armii Brytyjskiej, 1944 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Skróty Wojskowe Używane w Wojsku Angielskim, 1943 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Wojenna Organizacja i Wyposażenie Saperów Brytyjskich, 1941 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Zestawienie Wyrażeń Slangowych (Glossary of Army Slang), 1944 (Box-folder 1: 8)
- Armia Niemiecka (German Army), 1940-1945
  Comprised of German military manuals, outlining the army’s usage of weapons, tanks, tactical organization, usage of slang and military abbreviations, and infantry strategies.
  - Album Nimieckiego Sprzętu Pancernego, 1942 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Artyleria i Sprzęt Przeciwpancerny Niemieckiej Dywizji Pancernej, 1942 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Informacje o Armii Niemieckiej, 1944 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Krótkie Dane o Organizacji Wojska Niemieckiego, 1941 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Niemiecka Broń Maszynowa, 1942 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - Niemiecka Dywizja Pancerna, 1941 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - Niemiecka Dywizja Pancerna - Organizacja i działanie, 1942 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - Niemieckie działko pancerne P.A.K. 37 mm, 1942 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - Niemieckie Jednostki Pancerne w Akcji, 1941 (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - Niemieckie Oddziały Spadochronowe i Wojska Lądujące z Powietrza, 1940 (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - Niemieckie Taktyki Małych Oddziałów Piechoty, 1941 (Box-folder 1: 19)
  - Niemieckie Taktyki w Ramach Wzmocnionego Batalionu Piechoty, 1942 (Box-folder 1: 20)
  - Niemieckie Wojska i związki szybkie oraz dywizja pancerna, 1942 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - O Armii Niemieckiej w Czasie Wojny, 1943 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Organizacja i Taktyka Armii Niemieckiej, Część I, 1943 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Organizacja i Taktyka Armii Niemieckiej, Część II, 1943 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Oznaczniki Taktyczne (zeszyt nr. 3), 1942 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Oznaczniki Taktyczne (dalszy ciąg-zeszytu nr. 3), 1943 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Siły Zbrojne Niemiec, 1943 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Taktyka Niemiecka w Tunisii (Tunezja), 1944 (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - Taktyka Niemieckiej Piechoty i Jej Wsparcie Przez Inne Bronie, 1941 (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - Udział Niemieckiej Broni Pancernej i Lotnictwo w Kampanii Wrześniowej 1939 roku, 1940 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Uwagi Ogólne o Organizacji i Dyslokacji Wojsk Niemieckich w Afryce, 1942 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Użycie Dymów Bojowych w Armii Niemieckiej, 1943 (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - Użycie i Walka Niemieckiego Pułku i Baonu Czołgów, 1942 (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - Vade-Mecum Oficera Liniowego o Wojsku Niemieckim, 1945 (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - Wnioski z Kampanii Tuniskiej (Tunezyjskiej), 1942-1943 (Box-folder 2: 15)
  - Wyciąg No. 8 z Periodical Notes on the German Army No. 33, 1942 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Wyciąg No. 10 z Periodical Notes on the German Army No. 34, 1942 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - Wyciąg No. 12 z Periodical Notes on the German Army No. 34, 1942 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Wytyczne dla Identyfikacji Niemieckiego Sprzętu Pancernego, 1944 (Box-folder 3: 4)
- Armia Sowiecka (Soviet Army), 1945
  Comprised of Soviet military manuals, outlining the army’s tactics and organization.
  - Wojsko Sowieckie - Taktyka i Organizacja, 1945 (Box-folder 3: 5)
- Artyleria (Artillery), 1940-1946
  Composed of manuals discussing tactics, training, use of cannons, and various other weapons, regulations, and the neutralization of enemy artillery. Additionally, includes military issued Polish-English dictionaries.
  - Działa: Arkusz Poprawek, 1944 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Działa: Dostarczenie Raportów Meteorologicznych, 1943 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - Działa: Działo 3 Cala, 1944 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - Działa: Działo 5.5 Cala, 1946 (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - Działa: Działo 3 Cala - Tabele Strzelnicze, 1942 (Box-folder 3: 10)
  - Działa: Działo 25 Funtowe, 1941 (Box-folder 3: 11)
  - Działa: Działo 25 Funtowe - Działoczyny, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - Działa: Działo 25 Funtowe - Działoczyny, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Działa: Działo 25 Funtowe - Tabele Strzelnicze, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 4: 2-4)
  - Działa: Haubic 155mm - Tabele Strzelnicze, 1943 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Komunikat Informacyjny Nr. 2, 1943 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - Komunikat Informacyjny Nr. 4, 1943 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - Komunikat Informacyjny Nr. 5, 1943 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Komunikat Informacyjny Nr. 6, 1943 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - Moździerz Angielski “3 cal.” i “2 cal.”, 1942 (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - Moździerz 2 Calowy, 1945 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Moździerz 3 Calowy, 1942 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Moździerz 3 Calowy - Działoczyny, 1945 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - Moździerz 3 Calowy - Tabele Strzelnicze, 1942 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Moździerz 3 Calowy - Władanie i Zasady Strzelania, 1945 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - Moździerz 3 i 4.2 Calowy, 1945 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Moździerz 4.2 Calowy (Instrukcja Walki), 1944 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Moździerz Piechoty M 3, 1943 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - Szkoła Pododdziału (Artyleryjski Słownik), 1941 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Szkoła Pododdziału (Instrukcja o inspekcji sprzętu artyleryjskiego), 1945 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - Szkoła Pododdziału (Instrukcja o zabezpieczaniu sprzętu i przyrządów artyleryjskich przed dostępem wody), 1944 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - Szkoła Pododdziału (Kod Artyleryjski), 1943 (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - Szkoła Pododdziału (Regulamin Artylerii Musztra Motorowa), 1945 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - Szkoła Pododdziału (Schemat pakowania ciągników artyleryjskich), 1943 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Szkoła Pododdziału (Służba w Polu), 1942 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Szkoła Pododdziału (Strzelanie), 1941-1943 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Taktyka - Doraźne Ześrodkowanie Ognia, 1944 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Taktyka - Instrukcja Strzelania, 1942 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Taktyka - Nawiązanie Ogniowe, 1942 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - Taktyka - Ognie Planowane, 1944 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - Taktyka - Ogólna Instrukcja Strzelania Artylerii, 1942, 1945 (Box-folder 6: 8-9)
  - Taktyka - Organizacja Zwalczania Artylerii, 1945 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Taktyka - Pułk Pomiarowy Artylerii w Walce, 1943 (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - Taktyka - Regulamin Artylerii "Walka", 1942 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - Taktyka - Strzelanie Stromotorowe, 1944 (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - Topografia - Dalmierz Typ. FT 37, 1942 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Topografia - Instruckja Topograficzna Artylerii, 1942 (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Topografia - Liczenie Suwakiem, 1943 (Box-folder 7: 7)
  - Topografia - Pomiary Dalmierzem, 1943 (Box-folder 7: 8)
  - Topografia - Pomocnicze Tabele Topograficzne, 1943 (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - Topografia - Prace Stolikowe, 1942 (Box-folder 7: 10)
  - Topografia - Przyrządy Topograficzne, 1944 (Box-folder 7: 11)
  - Topografia - Suwak poprawek chwili do działa 25 funtowego, 1942 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Topografia - Topografia Artyleryjska, 1942 (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - Topografia - Wykres Sandesa, 1942 (Box-folder 8: 3)
  - Współpraca z Lotnictwem - Artyleria i Lotnictwo, 1942 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - Współpraca z Lotnictwem - Rozwijanie Dywizjonu Samolotów Artylerii, 1945 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - Współpraca z Lotnictwem - Strzelanie Artylerii z Lotnikami, 1942 (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - Współpraca z Lotnictwem - Współpraca Lotnictwa z Artylerią, 1943 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - Współpraca z Lotnictwem, 1945 (Box-folder 8: 8)
- Artyleria Przeciwlotnicza (Anti-Aircraft Artillery), 1941-1945
  Composed of manuals outlining the usage instructions and availability of specialized equipment, ammunition regulations, tactics, gun crew education, and description of available armament.
  - Amunicja - Regulamin Artylerii Przeciwlotniczej, Część I, 1942 (Box-folder 8: 9)
  - Amunicja - Regulamin Artylerii Przeciwlotniczej, Część III, 1944 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - Przyrządy Pomocnicze - Dalmierz No. 3 wz. III., 1944 (Box-folder 8: 11)
  - Przyrządy Pomocnicze - Działanie Przelicznika, 1941 (Box-folder 8: 12)
  - Przyrządy Pomocnicze - Komunikat Techniczny, 1944 (Box-folder 8: 13)
  - Przyrządy Pomocnicze - Luneta Rozpoznawcza, 1945 (Box-folder 8: 14)
  - Przyrządy Pomocnicze - Mechanizmy Przyrządów Pomiarowych, 1941 (Box-folder 8: 15)
  - Przyrządy Pomocnicze - Podstawy Teoretyczne i Zasady Działania Przelicznika, 1942 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Przyrządy Pomocnicze - Przeciw Lotnicza Luneta Obserwacyjna, 1944 (Box-folder 9: 2)
  - Przyrządy Pomocnicze - Przelicznik Artylerii Przeciwlotniczej, 1945 (Box-folder 9: 3)
  - Przyrządy Pomocnicze - Przyrząd “Stiffkey”, 1942 (Box-folder 9: 4)
  - Przyrządy Pomocnicze - Tabele Strzelnicze, 1942 (Box-folder 9: 5)
  - Przyrządy Pomocnicze - Transmisja Elektryczna, 1945 (Box-folder 9: 6)
  - Szkoła Działonu - Działoczyny, 1941-1944, 1943 (Box-folder 9: 7-8)
  - Szkoła Działonu - Działoczyny i Utrzymanie Sprzętu, 1943, 1945 (Box-folder 9: 9-10)
  - Szkoła Działonu - Komunikat Informacyjny, 1945 (Box-folder 9: 11)
  - Szkoła Działonu - Podstawowe Wiadomości z Balistyki, 1941 (Box-folder 9: 12)
  - Szkoła Działonu - Uzupełnienie Nr. 3, 1944 (Box-folder 9: 13)
  - Taktyka - Charakterystyka, 1941 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - Taktyka - Obrona Przeciwlotnicza Bierna, 1941 (Box-folder 10: 2)
  - Taktyka - Obrona Przeciwlotnicza w Świetle źródeł Nimieckich i Angielskich, 1942 (Box-folder 10: 3)
  - Taktyka - Służba w Polu, 1942 (Box-folder 10: 4)
  - Taktyka - Strzelanie, 1944 (Box-folder 10: 5-7)
  - Taktyka - Tymczasowy Regulamin, circa 1944 (Box-folder 10: 8)
  - Taktyka - Użycie Taktyczne, 1943 (Box-folder 11: 1-2)
  - Taktyka - Walka, 1941 (Box-folder 11: 3)
  - Taktyka - Wnioski z Obserwacji Ognia Rozpryskowego, 1941 (Box-folder 11: 4)
  - Uzbrojenie - 40 mm Armata Przeciwlotnicza - Atlas, 1943 (Box-folder 11: 5)
  - Uzbrojenie - 40 mm Armata Przeciwlotnicza - Ruchoma, 1942 (Box-folder 11: 6)
  - Uzbrojenie - 40 mm Armata Przeciwlotnicza - Słownictwo Angielsko-Polskie, 1944 (Box-folder 11: 7)
  - Uzbrojenie - 20 mm Działko Samoczynne Oerlikon, 1944 (Box-folder 12: 1-2)
- Artyleria Przeciwpancerna (Anti-Armored Artillery), 1941-1944
  Comprised of manuals discussing available armament and use of anti-tank artillery tactics.
  - Taktyka - Armaty PPANC, 1944 (Box-folder 12: 3)
  - Taktyka - Działoczyny przy 3 Calowym Dziale, 1944 (Box-folder 12: 4)
  - Taktyka - Działoczyny przy 17 funtowej armacie, 1943 (Box-folder 12: 5)
  - Taktyka - Działoczyny przy 6 funtowym dziale, 1943 (Box-folder 12: 6)
  - Taktyka - Rozwijanie do Walki Pułku Artylerii, 1944 (Box-folder 12: 7)
  - Taktyka - Technika i taktyka obrony przeciwczołgowej, 1943 (Box-folder 12: 8)
  - Taktyka - Uwagi o strzelaniu przeciw-pancernym, 1942 (Box-folder 12: 9)
  - Taktyka - Vademecum Dowódcy P-PANC, 1942 (Box-folder 12: 10)
  - Taktyka - Walka Przeciwpancerna, 1942 (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - Taktyka - Wskazówki dla działonowego i celowniczego do zwalczania czołgów, 1942 (Box-folder 13: 2)
  - Taktyka - Wyciąg - “Royal Artillery Training Memorandum”, 1943 (Box-folder 13: 3)
  - Taktyka - Wytyczne strzelania przeciwpancernego - sprzęt polowy, 1942 (Box-folder 13: 4)
  - Taktyka - Zwalczanie czołgów, 1942 (Box-folder 13: 5)
  - Uzbrojenie - Arkusz Poprawek, 1943 (Box-folder 13: 6)
  - Uzbrojenie - Działo 6 Funtowe, 1942 (Box-folder 13: 7)
  - Uzbrojenie - Regulamin Przeciwpancerny, 1941 (Box-folder 13: 8)
  - Uzbrojenie - Tabele Strzelnicze, 1943 (Box-folder 13: 9)
  - Uzbrojenie - Taktyka Przeciwpancerna, 1944 (Box-folder 13: 10)
- Broń Chemiczna (Chemical Weapons), 1941-1944
  Composed of manuals discussing anti-chemical weapons defenses, training, regulations, and using vapors in combat.
  - Dymy Bojowe - Gazy Bojowe, 1944 (Box-folder 13: 11)
  - Dymy Bojowe - Użycie Dymów Bojowych w Broni Pancernej, 1942 (Box-folder 13: 12)
  - Dymy Bojowe - Użycie Gazów Bojowych w Polu, 1943 (Box-folder 13: 13)
  - Dymy Bojowe - Taktyczne i techniczne użycie broni chemicznej, 1943 (Box-folder 13: 14)
  - Obrona Przeciwgazowa - Arkusz Poprawek, 1942 (Box-folder 13: 15)
  - Obrona Przeciwgazowa, 1944 (Box-folder 13: 16)
  - Obrona Przeciwgazowa - Regulamin, 1941 (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - Obrona Przeciwgazowa - Stosowanie Dymów Bojowych w Broni Pancernej, 1944 (Box-folder 14: 2)
  - Obrona Przeciwgazowa - Szkolenie w Obronie Przeciwgazowej, 1943 (Box-folder 14: 3)
- Broń Pancerna (Armored Weapons), 1941-1946
  Consists of various manuals on the topics of division tactics, tanks, soldier education, training, and the utilization of armored vehicles.
  - Czołgi - Czołg M4 i M4A1, 1945 (Box-folder 14: 4)
  - Czołgi - Czołg Piechoty Mark III, 1941 (Box-folder 14: 5)
  - Czołgi - Czołg Pościgowy, 1942 (Box-folder 14: 6)
  - Czołgi - Czołgi Sherman, 1945 (Box-folder 14: 7-8)
  - Czołgi - Czołgi Sherman, 1943, 1945 (Box-folder 15: 1-2)
  - Czołgi - Działo 75 mm M2 i M3 w Czołgu, 1944 (Box-folder 15: 3)
  - Samochody Pancerne - Carrier Uniwersalny, 1944 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - Samochody Pancerne - Czołgi i Samochody Pancerne, 1942 (Box-folder 15: 5)
  - Smochody Pancerne - Samochód Pancerny Daimler, 1942 (Box-folder 15: 6)
  - Smochody Pancerne - Samochód Pancerny Humber, 1942 (Box-folder 15: 7)
  - Smochody Pancerne - Samochód Zwiadowczy, 1942 (Box-folder 15: 8)
  - Szkolenie Podstawowe - Instrukcja rozpoznawania sprzętu pancernego, 1943 (Box-folder 16: 1)
  - Szkolenie Podstawowe - Musztra Pancerno Motorowa, 1941 (Box-folder 16: 2)
  - Szkolenie Podstawowe - Obowiązki Załogi Czołga, 1945 (Box-folder 16: 3)
  - Szkolenie Podstawowe - Podręcznik Kierowcy Czołga, 1945 (Box-folder 16: 4)
  - Szkolenie Podstawowe - Podręcznik Polowy, 1943 (Box-folder 16: 5)
  - Szkolenie Podstawowe - Regulacja i Użycie Busoli, 1943 (Box-folder 16: 6)
  - Szkolenie Podstawowe - Tabele Strzelnicze, 1943 (Box-folder 16: 7)
  - Szkolenie Podstawowe - Tymczasowe Przepisy, 1943 (Box-folder 16: 8)
  - Szkolenie Podstawowe - Wyszkolenie Załogi Czołga, 1941 (Box-folder 16: 9)
  - Szkolenie Podstawowe - Wzory Chorągiewek, 1943 (Box-folder 16: 10)
  - Szkolenie Podstawowe - Zapory Przeciwczołgowe, 1942 (Box-folder 16: 11)
  - Taktyka Oddziału i Pododdziału - Broń Pancerna No. 2, 1942 (Box-folder 16: 12)
  - Taktyka Oddziału i Pododdziału - Doktryna Taktycznego Użycia, 1943 (Box-folder 16: 13)
  - Taktyka Oddziału i Pododdziału - Dywizja Pancerna w Boju, 1945 (Box-folder 16: 14)
  - Taktyka Oddziału i Pododdziału - Organizacja, szkolenie i użycie dywizyjnego pułku kawalerii pancerno-motorowej, 1942 (Box-folder 16: 15)
  - Taktyka Oddziału i Pododdziału - Pluton Czołgów w Walce, w Marszu i na Postoju, 1946 (Box-folder 16: 16)
  - Taktyka Oddziału i Pododdziału - Pułk Pancerny, 1943 (Box-folder 17: 1)
  - Taktyka Oddziału i Pododdziału - Specjalne rozpoznanie czołgowe, 1942 (Box-folder 17: 2)
  - Taktyka Oddziału i Pododdziału - Szwadron Pancerny Walka, 1943 (Box-folder 17: 3)
  - Taktyka Oddziału i Pododdziału - Uwagi o Wyszkoleniu, Taktycznym Zastosowaniu i Organizacji, 1941 (Box-folder 17: 4)
  - Taktyka Oddziału i Pododdziału - Użycie Dywizji Pancernej, 1941 (Box-folder 17: 5)
  - Taktyka Oddziału i Pododdziału - Użycie Oddziałów Rozpoznawczych, 1945 (Box-folder 17: 6)
  - Taktyka Oddziału i Pododdziału - Użycie Taktycznego i Działania Czołgów Liniowych, 1943 (Box-folder 17: 7)
  - Taktyka Oddziału i Pododdziału - Wyszkolenie Plutonu Czołgów Pościgowych, 1942 (Box-folder 17: 8)
  - Współdziałanie z Innymi Rodzajami Broni - Broń pancerna i jej współdziałanie z innymi rodzajami broni, 1943 (Box-folder 17: 9)
  - Współdziałanie z Innymi Rodzajami Broni - Wskazówki Użycia Czołgów Wspierających Piechotę w Walce, 1944 (Box-folder 17: 10)
  - Współdziałanie z Innymi Rodzajami Broni - Współdziałanie czołgów z dywizjami piechoty, 1944 (Box-folder 17: 11)
  - Współdziałanie z Innymi Rodzajami Broni - Współpraca piechoty z czołgami, 1943 (Box-folder 17: 12)
- Broń Strzelecka (Firearms), 1941-1945
  Consists of various manuals on the topics of enemy ammunition and firearm, anti-armored and anti-aircraft ammunition and firearms, and artillery firearms.
  - Amunicja Artyleryjska - Amunicja 5.5 cal., 1942 (Box-folder 17: 13)
  - Amunicja Artyleryjska - Amunicja 6 funtowa, 1942 (Box-folder 17: 14)
  - Amunicja Artyleryjska - Amunicja 25 funtowa, 1941 (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - Amunicja Artyleryjska - Rozpoznawanie Pocisków Moździerzowych, 1944 (Box-folder 18: 2)
  - Amunicja Nieprzyjacielska, 1944 (Box-folder 18: 3)
  - Amunicja Nieprzyjacielska - Sposoby Postępowania z Amunicją Zdobyczną, 1944 (Box-folder 18: 4)
  - Amunicja Ogólnie - Podstawowe Wiadomości, 1945 (Box-folder 18: 5)
  - Amunicja Ogólnie - Północno Amerykański Sprzęt i Uzbrojenie, 1942 (Box-folder 18: 6)
  - Amunicja Ogólnie - Przepisy Służbowe o Niszczeniu Amunicji w Polu, 1941 (Box-folder 18: 7)
  - Amunicja Ogólnie - Rozpoznawanie i Postępowanie z Amunicją w Polu, 1944 (Box-folder 18: 8)
  - Amunicja Ogólnie - Słownik Amunicyjny, 1945 (Box-folder 18: 9)
  - Amunicja Ogólnie - Zestawienie Rozkazów i Zarządzeń Dowództwa 2. Korpusu, 1944 (Box-folder 18: 10)
  - Przeciwlotnicza i Przeciwpancerna - Instrukcja Strzelecka Przeciwlotnicza, 1941 (Box-folder 18: 11)
  - Przeciwlotnicza i Przeciwpancerna - Instrukcja Walki Miotaczem Przeciwpancernym, 1943 (Box-folder 18: 12)
  - Przeciwlotnicza i Przeciwpancerna - Regulamin Przeciwpancerny, 1941-1943 (Box-folder 19: 1)
  - Strzelecka Broń Piechoty - Ciężki Karabin Maszynowy - Browning, 1944 (Box-folder 19: 2)
  - Strzelecka Broń Piechoty - Ciężki Karabin Maszynowy - Vickers, 1942 (Box-folder 19: 3)
  - Strzelecka Broń Piechoty - Karabin Angielski, 1941 (Box-folder 19: 4)
  - Strzelecka Broń Piechoty - Lekki Karabin Maszynowy - Bren, 1941 (Box-folder 19: 5)
  - Strzelecka Broń Piechoty - Nauka o broni, 1942 (Box-folder 19: 6)
  - Strzelecka Broń Piechoty - Opis i Użycie Kątomierza, 1944 (Box-folder 19: 7)
  - Strzelecka Broń Piechoty - Organizacja i Użycie Taktyczne Ciężkich Karabinów Maszynowych, 1941 (Box-folder 19: 8)
  - Strzelecka Broń Piechoty - Pistolet Automatyczny - Thompson, 1942 (Box-folder 19: 9)
  - Strzelecka Broń Piechoty - Pistolet Maszynowy Sten Mk II, 1942 (Box-folder 19: 10)
- Lotnictwo (Air Force), 1941-1944
  Composed of manuals discussing the education and training of pilots, aircraft recognition and spotting tests, collaboration with infantry forces, and aircraft organization.
  - Fotografia Lotnicza, 1941 (Box-folder 19: 11)
  - Fotografia Lotnicza - Fotografia Lotnicza w Działaniach Wojennych, 1944 (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Fotografia Lotnicza - Lotnicze Zdjęcia Fotograficzne z Siatką, 1942 (Box-folder 20: 2)
  - Współdziałanie z Wojskami Lądowymi - Lotnicze Wyszkolenia Wojska, 1943 (Box-folder 20: 3)
  - Współdziałanie z Wojskami Lądowymi - Przeciwlotnicze Zasłony Dymne, 1943 (Box-folder 20: 4)
  - Współdziałanie z Wojskami Lądowymi - Rozpoznawania Samolotów, 1944 (Box-folder 20: 5)
  - Współdziałanie z Wojskami Lądowymi - Siły Powietrzne, 1943 (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - Współdziałanie z Wojskami Lądowymi - Siły Powietrzne jako wsparcie wojsk lądowych, 1942 (Box-folder 20: 7)
  - Współdziałanie z Wojskami Lądowymi - Spotting Test, circa 1943 (Box-folder 20: 8)
- Łączność (Communication), 1940-1946
  Comprised of manuals on the topics of radio stations, frequencies, equipment, education of soldiers, instructions, and regulations of connection traffic.
  - Obsługa Sprzętu - Instrukcja o Łącznicach, 1945 (Box-folder 20: 9)
  - Obsługa Sprzętu - Instrukcja strojenia radiostacji, 1945 (Box-folder 20: 10)
  - Obsługa Sprzętu - Musztra Strojenia Radiostacji, 1942 (Box-folder 20: 11)
  - Obsługa Sprzętu - Przewodnik kieszonkowy dla obsługi do zestrojenia i utrzymania r-stacji, 1944 (Box-folder 20: 12)
  - Radiostacje - Radiostacja Nr. 9, 1941 (Box-folder 20: 13)
  - Radiostacje - Radiostacja Nr. 11, 1941 (Box-folder 20: 14)
  - Radiostacje - Radiostacja Nr. 18, 1941 (Box-folder 20: 15)
  - Radiostacje - Radiostacja Nr. 19, 1942 (Box-folder 20: 16)
  - Radiostacje - Radiostacja Nr. 21, 1943 (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - Radiostacje - Radiostacja Nr. 38, 1944 (Box-folder 21: 2)
  - Radiostacje - Radiostacja Nr. 46, 1944 (Box-folder 21: 3)
  - Radiostacje - Urządzenia dodatkowe przy radiostacjach, 1941 (Box-folder 21: 4)
  - Ruch Łączności - Łączność ziemi z samolotem współpracy, 1941 (Box-folder 21: 5)
  - Ruch Łączności - Ruch Dalekopisowy, 1946 (Box-folder 21: 6)
  - Ruch Łączności - Ruch Radiowy, 1942 (Box-folder 21: 7)
  - Ruch Łączności - Ruch Radiotelefoniczny, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 21: 8-9)
  - Ruch Łączności - Ruch Radiotelegraficzny, 1945 (Box-folder 21: 10)
  - Ruch Łączności - Sygnalizacja Optyczna, 1940 (Box-folder 21: 11)
  - Ruch Łączności - Znaki Ruchu Łączności, 1941 (Box-folder 21: 12)
  - Sprzęt Łączności - Różne - Aparat telefoniczny F. Mk. I. i Mk. I. z gwiazdką, 1943 (Box-folder 22: 1)
  - Sprzęt Łączności - Różne - Aparat telefoniczny Typu D, Mark V, 1940 (Box-folder 22: 2)
  - Sprzęt Łączności - Różne - Aparat telegraficzny Fuller Phone Mark IV, 1941 (Box-folder 22: 3)